so we will see Now that Another Benefit
of Loop and Rolling is that it allows us
to also reduce the cpi in addition to
reducing the number of instructions to
get some Idea for How The cpi Changes We
need to have a processor So let's assume
We have a Four issue in Order processor
meaning It's Only able to Look at the
Next Four instructions to see What can
be executed together meaning It can Only
Look at the Next Four instructions to
see What It can execute together and let
assume that The processor has Perfect
branch priction so First  Let's Look at
What Happens When we try to execute the
original Loop so to see What Happens
with this Loop In this processor Let's
Look Cycle by Cycle at which
instructions can execute in the very
First Cycle we will Try to do this Load
and then we will Try to see whether We
can execute The Next instruction in
Order in the same Cycle but We cannot
Because it depends on the Load so this
instruction has to be Done Here Now we
will Look at the Next instruction and
Try to execute it in Order  in the same
Cycle but We cannot Because it depends
on  R2 Again so We Move Here The Next
instruction however does not depend on
the previous one so We can do this Add
Here but then for the branch it does
depend on R1 so It can be Only Done Here
Because We have Perfect branch traction
this Load has also been fetched from the
Next iteration and it doesn't depend on
the branch that was Done Here so we will
actually do The Load for the Next
iteration and then we will Again not Be
able to do The Add so The Add Happens in
the Next Cycle and then In  this Cycle
these Two happen and so on so overall
After this initial Load that had to be
Done by itself Just Because there was No
branch before it it takes US Three
cycles to do All Five of the
instructions in the Loop so The cpi Here
is Three cycles for Five instructions
but Remember that We can do scheduling
of of this Loop to Try to improve the
cpi so before We get into What's the cpi
of the unroad Loop Let's see what the
cpi is if We schedule this Loop Body our
scheduling will  Start Out with this Loop
Body and then Try to maximize  the cpi
that We can Get By reordering the
instructions so clearly Here this Load
could not Be Done in Parallel with the
Next instruction Because There is a
dependency there so We need to Find
Something and it cannot be the branch
Because It needs To Stay At The End Of
The iteration that We can put Here and
this adi can Move there so our
scheduling algorithm will Move The adi
Here so Now that We are subtracting Four
from R1 Here We need to adjust this
Store so that it adds Back The Four that
We decremented Here Because this Store
was supposed to Store to the same
Element as The Load Now however we have
moved R1 so to Access the same Element
as The Load We need to Add Four here
Here Note that Moving The adi is really
the only scheduling Freedom We have Here
Because We need to do The Load and the
AD and the store in that Order so They
cannot be reordered the branch needs to
Stay At The End Of The Loop so Pretty
much the only Freedom We have is Where
is the adi going to happen  so Now Let's
Look at What Happens  Cycle by Cycle We
can do The Load in the First Cycle The
adi can Now Be Done together with the
Load but The Add to What We loaded Still
has to be Done in the Next Cycle The
Store cannot be Done until this AD is
Complete the branch can Still proceed in
Parallel with the Store and now Because
Of Perfect branch piiction we're going
to Move Here and We can Try to do The
Load for the Next iteration Note that R1
has been updated Here in the previous
iteration so All the Way Through Here We
really did not modify  R1 so Pretty much
The Store or The branch didn't modify R1
That's the only register dependency that
this Load has so The Load can be Done
Here and then We can also do The R1
update Here Because this adi Only
depends on R1 and the R1 has been
updated Here so We can do this so as you
can see now it takes two cycles to do
this Five instructions so The cpi We Get
is now 2 over F it Took US two cycles to
do The Five instructions This is
significantly better than  Without
scheduling so scheduling did help